FERNANDO SILVA

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

E-mail | GitHub | LinkedIn | MyPortfolio

SUMMARY

Computing engineer with a background in developing efficient software applications in a global market. 5+ years of industry experience, including mentoring junior developers to achieve concrete goals on a strict deadline. I can deliver software solutions using Javascript, React/Redux, and Ruby/Rails stacks and I also can learn new programming languages quickly. I have solid experience collaborating effectively in remote teams using pair programming and agile methodology. Currently, I'm looking for job opportunities within the software development industry.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, Postgres

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring.

Soft Skills: Teamwork, Communication, Leadership.

EXPERIENCE

MICROVERSE Remote
Full-stack Web Developer Jan, 2022 – Present

AwesomeBooks – Web Application prototype of a portfolio for professional projects exhibition.

• Built with: HTML / CSS / Javascript

WebDevWeek — Fictitious Event Webpage created to practice web development for desktop and mobile environments.

• Built with: HTML / CSS / JavaScript

MICROVERSE - Remote - Mentor (Volunteer) -

Febr, 2022 - Present

• Mentoring junior web developers, and providing technical support through code reviews and advice.

CERVEJARIAS KAISER BRASIL - M. Mirim, SP, Brazil - Software Development Analyst Mar, 1991 – Apr,1992 (1 year)

- Developed Payroll application (reducing the time of payroll calculations. Language: Cobol)
- Developed Production Control application (replacing manual controls for the production area. Language: Cobol)

MARSICANO - Salto, SP, Brazil - Software Development Analyst

Oct, 1989 - Mar, 1991 (2 years)

- Developed Payroll application (reviewed calculations process and refactoring). Language: Clipper)
- Developed Sales Control application (replacing manual controls for the sales area. Language: Clipper)

GRUPO CHIARELLI - Salto, SP, Brazil - Applications Development Analyst

Apr, 1984 – Mar, 1989 (5 years)

- Developed Application for payroll (replacing manual controls spreadsheets. Language: Cobol)
- Developed billing application for vehicles (reducing time and improving business process. Language: Cobol).

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE Remote Full-Stack, Web Development Program, Full Time Jan, 2022 - Present

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React/Redux, Database management with Postgres and MySQL.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard gitflow, and daily stand-up meetings to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

UNIVESP - Virtual University of São Paulo, SP, BRAZIL (EAD) **BA, Computing Engineering**

Aug, 2018 - Present

FGV FUNDAÇÃO GETÚLIO VARGAS - SP - BRAZIL MBA, Business and IT Strategic Management

Oct. 2006